<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<resources>

    <string name="intro">The Italian fiscal code (\"Codice Fiscale\"), similar to the Social Security Number (SSN) in the United States
        or the National Insurance Number issued in the United Kingdom, is a 16-character alphanumeric code.
        It serves to unequivocally identify natural persons resident in Italy regardless of their residence status.
        \Created by the Italian tax office, it is currently used for a number of other purposes, such as identifying
        unambiguously individuals in the health care system, or natural persons acting as parties to private contracts.
        \The code is issued by the Italian Inland Revenue, the <i>Agenzia delle Entrate</i>.
    </string>

    <string name="ch1_title"><b>Computation of the fiscal code</b></string>
    <string name="ch1_text">
        For natural persons, the code consists of 16 alphanumeric characters, and is generated using the following algorithm.
    </string>

    <string name="ch_surname_title"><b>Last name (3 letters)</b></string>
    <string name="ch_surname_text">
        Consonants present in the surname(s) are considered (for women, only the maiden name is considered).
        If the surname contains more than three consonants, they are taken in the order in which they appear.
        If the consonants are not sufficient, the vowels are taken and positioned after the consonants.
        Finally, if the surname has less than three letters, the letter X is appended to the code generated.
    </string>
    <string name="ch_surname_eg">\n
        - Rossi → RSS\n
        - Mori → MRO\n
        - Al → LAX\n
    </string>

    <string name="ch_name_title"><b>First name (3 letters)</b></string>
    <string name="ch_name_text">
        The consonants of the name(s) are taken. If the name contains four or more consonants,
        the first, the third and the fourth are taken, otherwise the first three in the order
        in which they appear. If there are not enough consonants, the vowels, always positioned after
        the consonants. If the name has less than three letters, the code is completed by adding the letter X.
    </string>
    <string name="ch_name_eg">\n
        - Martha → MRT\n
        - Gabriel→ GRL\n
        - Marie → MRA\n
        - Eli → LEI\n
        - Ed → DEX\n
        - Li → LIX\n
    </string>

    <string name="ch_year_month_title"><b>Year and month of birth (3 characters)</b></string>
    <string name="ch_year_month_text">
        Year (two digits): last two digits of the year of birth.
        \nMonth (one letter): letter corresponding to the month according to the table below.
    </string>
    <string name="ch_year_month_eg">\n
        - January 1999 → 99A\n
        - August 2005 → 05M\n
        - April 1983 → 83D\n
    </string>

    <string name="ch_day_gender_title"><b>Date of Birth and Gender (2 digits)</b></string>
    <string name="ch_day_gender_text">
        For Men, the digits of the day of birth are taken, prepending a 0 if the day is less than 10
        (the number therefore ranges from 01 to 31). For women, 40 is added to the day of birth (41-71).
    </string>

    <string name="ch_pob_title"><b>Place of Birth (4 characters, one letter and 3 digits)</b></string>
    <string name="ch_pob_text">
        Each Italian municipality (\"comune\") corresponds to a code, composed of a letter followed by three digits,
        called the Cadastral Code or Land Registry Code. \nFor those born outside the Italian territory
        (Italian citizens or foreigners born abroad, or born in Italy but of foreign origin) a code is used to refer
        to the country of birth. The codes for foreign countries begin with the letter Z.
    </string>
    <string name="ch_pob_eg">\n
        - Abano Terme → A001\n
        - Trento → L378\n
        - France → Z110\n
    </string>

    <string name="ch_control_title"><b>Control character (one letter)</b></string>
    <string name="ch_control_text_1">
        The control character is calculated from the fifteen alphanumeric characters obtained
        up to this point, following this algorithm:\n
            - Separate the characters that are in even positions from those in odd positions;\n
            - Each character is converted into a numerical value by following these tables:\n
    </string>

    <string name="ch_control_text_2">
            - The values obtained must be added together, and the result should be divided by 26. The remainder of the
        division will be the index of the letter of the alphabet, which represents the control character:
    </string>
    <string name="ch_control_eg">\n
        - 0 → A\n
        - 1 → B\n
        …\n
        - 25 → Z\n
    </string>

    <string name="ch_identical_title"><b>Identical codes</b></string>
    <string name="ch_identical_text">
        In the rare cases in which two people are found to have the same fiscal code
        (e.g. two people with very similar first and last names, born on the same day and in the same town),
        the Revenue Agency replaces the numeric characters from the right, according to the table below.
        \nThe control character will then be recalculated.
    </string>

    <string name="ch_suppressed_title"><b>Cases of town name change</b></string>
    <string name="ch_suppressed_text">
        It may happen that the list of municipalities (or countries), and therefore of cadastral codes, varies over time, for example if two or more
        cities are aggregated into a single municipality (e.g. the municipality of Gravedona ed Uniti, formed in 2011 by the merger of the
        previous towns Consiglio di Rumo, Germasino and Gravedona). In these cases it can happen that a person was born in a town
        that no longer exists today or no longer has its original name, and therefore that the database of the application, updated with the latest
        list of municipalities, does not contain it. If your town or country of birth is not on the list, we would be grateful if you would let us know,
        through a review or an anonymous feedback (Settings > Send Feedback), so that we can add it to the database.
    </string>

</resources>
